earthclassmail.com 2018-12-04

# Privacy Policy | Earth Class Mail

This is the privacy policy of Earth Class Mail, Inc. (ECM) applicable to the website at www.EarthClassMail.com (“the Website”) and, should you become a customer, to our secure hosted software application, which requires registration and payment and may include online postal mail, check processing, or for other mail-related services that we perform (“the Hosted Services”). 

Not for Children. None of our websites, applications or services are intended for children. Please do not submit information about yourself using our websites if you are under 13. If you are the parent or guardian of a child under 13 who may have submitted information to us please contact us at [privacy@earthclassmail.com](mailto:privacy@earthclassmail.com).

We take very seriously the jobs of providing high quality service and protecting your privacy. The information below outlines the commitment we have made to protect your privacy. We do reserve the right to change this agreement, but any changes made will be posted here.

Please contact us at [privacy@earthclassmail.com](mailto:privacy@earthclassmail.com) if you wish to exercise your right to access, amend, or delete any personal data we hold about you; or you have any other questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy.

## The Website

When you visit the Website as a guest, our web server will capture your IP address, the time and duration of your visit, and the pages on the Site that you visit. It may also collect information about your browser, device (including your mobile device), location and other information of the type collected by web servers generally. We use cookies, web beacons, and other techniques to identify your browser and device to your guest activity on the Site. 

## The Hosted Services

When you sign up for a Hosted Service that requires registration, we ask you for personal information (such as your name, email address, and an account password). For services such as online postal mail, we also request and store credit card or other payment account information, address and telephone information, and physical copies of your identification papers. For services such as check processing and depositing, we will request and store information relating to your banking account. All information will be maintained in encrypted form on secure servers or in secure physical facilities, as appropriate. We may combine the information you submit under your account with information from other ECM services or third parties to provide you with a better experience and to improve the quality of our services. For certain services, we may give you the opportunity to opt out of combining such information. We do not contact site visitors unless they have given us explicit permission to do so, have written to us, or have begun (or completed) the process of signing up for one of our services. Except in the unlikely event that we are required to do so by law, personal details of your visit to our publicly-accessible website will never be shared with any third party without your permission.

## Cookies

Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. We use cookies in order to implement authentication and to enable core features of our application, as well as to enable us to better understand user behavior. We use cookies to compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business. If you prefer, you can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies via your browser settings. However, if you turn your cookies off, most of our services may not function properly.

## Analytics Tools.

We may use third party web analytics tools to capture information about your use of the Site, such as mouse clicks and scrolling activity. For example, we may use Google Analytics, Google Website Optimizer, or Segment. The providers of these tools may capture data about your activity on our Site, via cookies and other techniques.

## Information You Submit.

We may ask you to volunteer information about yourself using the Website. For example, we may ask you to provide your name, phone number, and email address, and information about your general interest in the ECM. Your submission of this type of information as a guest on the Website is not required.

## Partners

We may work with a partner site, such as a vendor, to offer you certain services. The partners do NOT, without your knowledge and consent, collect your identity or contact information from your visits to their websites. We provide information to trusted partners who work on behalf of or with ECM under confidentiality agreements. These companies may use your personal information to help ECM communicate with you about offers from ECM and our marketing partners. However, these companies do not have any independent right to share this information.

For each visitor to a partner website, the visitor's computer reaches the partner via a particular IP (Internet Protocol) address, and the partner's servers automatically collect this IP address.

Cookies assist partners in tracking your activities from our web site to a partner's web site that you link to from our site. If you re-visit the partner's site directly, the partner is able to continue to track your activities on the site and reward us for referring you. The Cookies themselves tell the partner nothing about you personally.

Cookies are used in two stages of the partner tracking: when a banner image on our site is loaded on your Web page for viewing by you and when you click a banner on our site. The function of these Cookies is to provide the partner with information solely for the purpose of crediting us with referrals.

The partner's servers automatically generate a unique number identifying your visit. No information is obtained from you or your computer to generate your unique identifying number. None of the partner's Cookies are used to perform "User Profiling".

## Log information

When you use ECM services, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.

## User communications

When you send email or other communication to ECM, we may retain those communications to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services.

## Affiliated sites

We may offer some of our services in connection with other web sites. In such cases, personal information that you provide to those sites may be sent to ECM to deliver the service. We process such information in accordance with this Policy. The affiliated sites may have different privacy practices and we encourage you to read their privacy policies.

## Links

ECM may present links in a format that enables us to keep track of whether these links have been followed. We may use this information to improve the quality of any customized content or advertising that we may offer.

## Other sites

This Privacy Policy applies to websites and services that are owned and operated by ECM. We do not exercise control over third-party sites. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data, or solicit personal information from you.

ECM only processes personal information for the purposes described in the applicable Privacy Policy and/or privacy notice for specific services. In addition to the above, such purposes include:

  * Reporting to credit bureaus;
  * Providing our products and services to users, including the scanning of envelope images, the display of those scanned images in notification emails to you and in your online account, the display and routing of the scanned contents of mail, and solicited advertising content;
  * Sending you certain communications relating to ECM services, such as service announcements, administrative messages, and the ECM newsletter, all of which are considered part of your ECM account and do not require us to offer you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them;
  * Site usage tracking, to enable us to monitor Web site traffic and usage patterns to continually enhance and improve the service we offer, and for customer source information. In this process, we may collect IP addresses (which indicate the location of your computer on the Internet) to ensure effective technical operations. We may provide anonymous reporting for internal and external clients.
  * Auditing, research, and analysis to maintain, protect, and improve our services;
  * Ensuring the technical functioning of our network; and
  * Developing new services.

You can find more information about how we process personal information by referring to the privacy notices for particular services.

ECM processes personal information on our servers in the United States of America and reserves the right to process personal information in other countries. In some cases, we may process personal information on behalf of and per the instructions of a third party.

## Choices for personal information

When you sign up for a service that requires registration, we notify you of our User Agreement and Privacy Policy. We also ask you to provide personal information. If we use this information in a manner different from the purpose for which it was collected, then we will ask for your consent prior to such use.

If we propose to use personal information for any purposes other than those described in this Policy and/or in the specific service notices, we will offer you an effective way to opt out of the use of personal information for those other purposes. We will not collect or use sensitive personal information for purposes other than those described in this Policy or the specific service notices, unless we have obtained your prior consent (such as in our service agreements). **You can decline to submit personal information to any of our services, in which case ECM may not be able to provide those services to you.**

## Information sharing

ECM does not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or non-affiliated companies except to provide products or services you've requested or under the following circumstances. You may not opt-out of this sharing:

  * If we provide such information to our subsidiaries, affiliated companies, or other trusted businesses or persons for processing personal information on our behalf. We require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures, including adequate data protection principles.
  * If we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation, or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process (including without limitation subpoenas and court orders), or enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce applicable terms of service, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues, (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property, or safety of ECM, its users or the public as required or permitted by law, or (e) to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.
  * If ECM becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all its assets, we will provide notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.
  * We may share with third parties certain pieces of aggregated, non-personal information, such as the number of users who searched for a particular term, for example, or how many users clicked on a particular advertisement. Such information does not identify you individually.
  * We may disclose information to non-affiliated third parties for routine business reasons. For example, we may disclose information to service providers and other third parties as necessary to facilitate a transaction or the Services, or to report to credit bureaus.
  * Please contact us at the address below for any additional questions about the management or use of personal data.

## Information security

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure, or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage, and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data.

We restrict access to personal information to ECM employees, contractors, and agents who need to know that information to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.

Earth Class Mail applies rigorous security measures at physical mail facilities, at its data centers, and within the applications that it provides for access to those services.

## Data integrity

ECM processes personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Policy or any applicable service-specific privacy notice. We review our data collection, storage, and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store, and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our services. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we process is accurate, complete, and current, but we depend on our users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary.

## Accessing and updating personal information

When you use our Hosted Services, we make good-faith efforts to provide you with access to your personal information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected, or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, jeopardize the privacy of others. In any case where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort.

## Enforcement

Enforcement – Customer Service is staffed to assist and support our customers’ activities and accounts, and to enforce adherence to our User Agreement terms and conditions. Customer Service can suspend and/or terminate service for any account for breach of those terms or operating in a manner inconsistent with the terms of service. Earth Class Mail’s Human Resources department also works closely with department heads to ensure policies are adhered to and when necessary to terminate employment for any employee, permanent or temporary, that breaches the terms of hire, or presents a security risk.

ECM regularly reviews its compliance with this Policy. Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this Policy or ECM's treatment of personal information by contacting us through this web site or by writing to us at Your Privacy Rights, c/o Earth Class Mail, 9450 SW Gemini Dr, #101, Beaverton, Oregon 97008-7105. When we receive formal written complaints at this address, it is ECM's policy to contact the complaining user regarding his or her concerns. We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between ECM and an individual.

European residents with inquiries regarding data privacy can contact us at the above address or at [privacy@earthclassmail.com](mailto:privacy@earthclassmail.com).

## Changes to this policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below. This policy was last modified on May 18, 2018.

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

Earth Class Mail  
122 E. Houston St, 2nd Floor  
San Antonio, TX 78205  
[privacy@earthclassmail.com](mailto:privacy@earthclassmail.com).
